CHRISTOPHER DALY

PERSONAL DETAILS

Apt. 14, 112 The Rock Bury Greater Manchester, BL9 OPZ

Mobile: +447798 614 977 Email: c.daly888@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Java Software Engineer with over 2 years of experience, having worked on bespoke projects from beginning to end based on customer requirements. I have gained experience using the whole Atlassian Suite which has helped me to collaborate and build projects ready to be used by the end user, together with Big Data technologies including Hadoop, Relational and Non-Relational Databases. I have excellent communication, problem solving and organisational skills gained during my employment history. Experiences within employment and education have developed both individual and team working skills. This has enabled me to work effectively in a team to achieve specific goals.

My work experience has developed an understanding of the corporate and tech environment, and enhanced the ability to manage work load and meet deadlines. Whilst working in earlier admin/clerical roles I learned how to process customer information, and communicated with the public and other parts of the organisation. During this period, I took part in volunteering with the British Red Cross as an event first-aider. This challenged me with responsibility and developed skills which could save someone's life. Both through study and working at Raytheon, I have increased my competence in programming languages, software and operating systems, as well as cloud technology (AWS).

In my spare time I like to keep active by going to the gym and attending swimming lessons to improve my technique. I cook most days, to make fresh tasty food. I keep up to date with technology news such as gadgets and new scientific innovations.

I have a passion for acquiring knowledge and advancing skills in Software Engineering and using new technologies. I am keen to join a company where I can undertake structured professional development to enhance my Software Engineering knowledge, and to develop my passion for building a successful career within this field.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

May 2017-July 2019 Software Engineer, Raytheon Systems Ltd, Manchester

- Java Software Engineer working as a contractor on a civil service site.
 - Experience working in both security restricted and unrestricted environments
 - Acclimatised to customer's rules and culture
- Working in a small agile team on bespoke projects:
 - Creating Spring Boot REST APIs
 - Using Java + Spring to create API that works with another team's code
 - Using pre-existing library's whether bespoke team or standard
 - Implementing Hadoop Big Data Clusters
 - Using Hadoop technologies such as Spark, Hue, HDFS, Hive
 - Database solutions Apache Accumulo
 - Undertaking DevOps work using the following technologies to provision virtual systems and software:
 - Vagrant create Virtual Machines (VM)
 - Ansible install software on provisioned VM
 - Docker create containers which will run software such as 'Zookeeper' (Hadoop)

- Participating in agile team meetings
 - Daily stand-up in order to share what each member did the day before and what they are doing today
 - Sprint:
 - Retrospectives to discuss what was good and bad during the last sprint
 - Planning discuss what needs to be done in the next sprint
 - Reviews go over what was achieved in the last sprint and what was learned
- Using tools from Atlassian:
 - o Bitbucket for code version control
 - o Bamboo for building and deployment
 - Confluence for documentation

Sep 2014-Sep 2015 Administrator, Traffic Penalty Tribunal (Local Government), Wilmslow

- Administrator for the Traffic Penalty Tribunal
 - o Processing public appeals
 - o Connecting parties to adjudicator for telephone hearings
 - o Communicated with local councils in England & Wales regarding cases

Aug 2011-July 2014 Clerical Officer, (Manpower) Royal Bank of Scotland Group, Manchester

- Clerical Officer working as a contractor for RBS
 - o Processing customer complaints
 - o Experience communicating with other departments of the bank

ENGINEERING COMPETANCIES

Languages

- Java Advanced
- Scala Intermediate
- HTML Competent
- CSS Competent

Software

- MS Windows Advanced
- Eclipse Competent
- Notepad++ Competent
- Atom Competent
- Android Studio Competent

Code Build Automation Tools

• Gradle – Competent

Cloud

AWS – Basic

- JavaScript Competent
- SQL Competent
- Android Competent
- MySQL Competent
- Oracle SQL Developer Competent
- IntelliJ Competent
- Linux Competent
- Atlassian Suite Intermediate

Maven - Competent

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Sep 2015-Sep 2016 MSc Computing – Manchester Metropolitan University

- Completed a Master's degree in Computing: (Merit)
- Subjects included Information & Digital Media Systems, Web Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Enterprise Programming and Mobile & Ubiquitous Computing
- Completed dissertation on The Security of a Java Based Web Application: (Distinction)
- Trained in SQL using Oracle Academy Material

2007-2010 BSc (Hons) Global Hazards – University of Derby

- Completed a Bachelor's degree in Global Hazards: (2:2)
- Subjects included: Climate Change, Volcanology, Geography of the Global Economy, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), Environmental Policy & Management and Radiation Pollution
- Dissertation on the effects of Coastal Landslides in North Yorkshire
- Field trips to NW Pacific (USA) & Tenerife
- Hazard Modelling Software Erupt3
- Use of GIS software ArcGIS & Idrisi

2004-2007 A-levels, Aquinas College, Stockport

- 4 A-levels including Computing, Environmental Science, Geology and General Studies
- Programmed in Visual Basic and .ASP (Pre-.net)
- Statistical Analysis using MS Excel

2001-2004 GCSEs, Hulme Hall Grammar School, Cheadle Hulme, Stockport

• 6 passes at A-C Grade including English, Maths, Double Award Science, ICT & French

VOLUNTEERING

Aug 2010-Jan 2015 Event First Aid Volunteer with the British Red Cross

- Volunteered with the British Red Cross as a First Aider, providing first-aid to a wide variety of events including amusement parks and charity sporting events.
- Tasks ranged from dealing with cuts and sprains to unconsciousness and life-threatening injuries.
- Responsibilities included providing first-aid and casualty care to anyone that needs it during the event and continual training to enhance skills
- Attended at group sessions every few weeks to discuss upcoming events, improve skills through training.
- · Was able to help people in need and learn skills that would be useful in any medical emergency

INTERESTS

Self-Study

- Improving Coding Ability
- Looking into new features of software and releases

Tech News

- Topics
 - Cyber Security/Threats
 - o Artificial Intelligence
 - o Trends in new hardware
- Can stay updated on any new developments that could use in the future

Cooking

• Love to cook, and always looking for opportunities to be creative with food.

Gym

- Regular swimming lessons in order to improve technique and feel more confident in the water
- Weekly cardio workout to improve fitness

REFERENCES

Available upon request